<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Web Design | Aaron Gustafson]]></title>
  <link href="http://aaron-gustafson.com//notebook/tags/web-design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://aaron-gustafson.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-14T17:50:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://aaron-gustafson.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aaron Gustafson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Fundamental Disconnect]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaron-gustafson.com/notebook/2014/a-fundamental-disconnect/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-13T15:01:58-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaron-gustafson.com/notebook/2014/a-fundamental-disconnect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday at <a href="2014.blendconf.com/">BlendConf</a>, <a href="http://www.hanselman.com/">Scott Hanselman</a> gave a fantastically-entertaining keynote entitled “JavaScript, The Cloud, and the rise of the New Virtual Machine.” In it, he chronicled all of the ways Web development and deployment has changed—for the better—over the years. He also boldly declared that JavaScript is now, effectively, a virtual machine in the browser.</p>

<p>This is a topic that has been weighing on my mind for quite some time now. I’ll start by saying that I’m a big fan of JavaScript. I write a lot of it and I find it incredibly useful, both as a programming language and as a way to improve the usability and accessibility of content on the Web. That said, I know it’s limitations. But I’ll get to that in a minute.</p>

<p>In the early days of the Web, “proper” software developers shied away from JavaScript. Many viewed it as a “toy” language (and felt similarly about HTML and CSS). It wasn’t as powerful as Java or Perl or C in their minds, so it wasn’t really worth learning. In the intervening years, however, JavaScript has changed a lot.</p>

<p>Most of these developers first began taking JavaScript seriously in the mid ’00s when Ajax became popular. And with the rise of JavaScript MVC frameworks and their ilk—Angular, Ember, etc.—many of these developers made their way onto the Web. I would argue that this, overall, is a good thing: We need more people working on the Web to make it better.</p>

<p>The one problem I’ve seen, however, is the fundamental disconnect many of these developers seem to have with the way deploying code on the Web works. In traditional software development, we have some say in the execution environment. On the Web, we don’t.</p>

<p>I’ll explain.</p>

<p>If we’re writing server-side software in Python or Rails or even PHP, one of two things is true:</p>

<ol>
<li>We control the server environment: operating system, language versions, packages, etc.; or</li>
<li>We don’t control the server environment, but we have knowledge of it and can author your program accordingly so it will execute as anticipated.</li>
</ol>


<p>In the more traditional installed software world, we can similarly control the environment by placing certain restrictions on what operating systems our code can run on and what the dependencies for its use may be in terms of hard drive space and RAM required. We provide that information up front and users can choose to use our software or use a competing product based on what will work for them.</p>

<p>On the Web, however, all bets are off. The Web is ubiquitous. The Web is messy. And, as much as we might like to control a user’s experience down to the very pixel, those of us who have been working on the Web for a while understand that it’s a fool’s errand and <a href="http://dowebsitesneedtolookexactlythesameineverybrowser.com/">have adjusted our expectations accordingly</a>. Unfortunately, this new crop of Web developers doesn’t seem to have gotten that memo.</p>

<p>We do not control the environment executing our JavaScript code, interpreting our HTML, or applying our CSS. Our users control the device (and, thereby, it’s processor speed, RAM, etc.). Our users choose the operating system. Our users pick the browser and which version they use. Our users can decide which add-ons they put in the browser. Our users can shrink or enlarge the fonts used to display our Web pages and apps. And the Internet providers that sit between us and our users, dictating the network speed, latency, and ultimately <a href="http://aaron-gustafson.com/notebook/2014/the-network-effect/">controlling how—and what part of—our content makes it to our users</a>.</p>

<p>All we can do is author an compelling, adaptive experience, cross our fingers, and hope for the best.</p>

<p>The fundamental problem with viewing JavaScript as the new VM is that it creates the illusion of control. Sure, if we are building an internal Web app, we might be able to dictate the OS/browser combination for all of our users and lock down their machines to prevent them from modifying those settings, but that’s not the reality on the open Web.</p>

<p>The fact is that we can’t absolutely rely on the availability of any specific technology when it comes to delivering a Web experience. Instead, we must look at <em>how</em> we construct that experience and make smarter decisions about how we use specific technologies in order to take advantage of their benefits while simultaneously understanding that they’re availability is not guaranteed. This is why progressive enhancement is such a useful philosophy.</p>

<p>The history of the Web is littered with JavaScript disaster stories. That doesn’t mean we shouldn’t use JavaScript or that it’s inherently bad. It simply means we need to be smarter about our approach to JavaScript and build robust experiences that allow users to do what they need to do even quickly an easily even if our carefully-crafted, incredibly well-designed JavaScript-driven interface won’t run.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Network Effect]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaron-gustafson.com/notebook/2014/the-network-effect/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-08T16:40:44-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaron-gustafson.com/notebook/2014/the-network-effect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><cite>Ars Technica</cite> revealed today that <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2014/09/why-comcasts-javascript-ad-injections-threaten-security-net-neutrality/">Comcast is injecting self-promotional advertising into web pages delivered via it’s Wi-Fi hotspots</a>:</p>

<blockquote cite="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2014/09/why-comcasts-javascript-ad-injections-threaten-security-net-neutrality/">
    <p>A Comcast spokesman told Ars the program began months ago. One facet of it is designed to alert consumers that they are connected to Comcast's Xfinity service. Other ads remind Web surfers to download Xfinity apps, Comcast spokesman Charlie Douglas told Ars in telephone interviews.</p>
</blockquote>


<p>I wish I could say this is surprising, but it’s not: Any service that routes your content has the opportunity to modify the response being returned. Comcast is exploiting that opportunity and injecting JavaScript that, in turn, injects the ads.</p>

<p>The fact that middlemen can manipulate server responses is one reason <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cBhZ6S0PFCY">Google is pushing for all sites to be served under HTTPS</a>. With traffic running to and from your server in an encrypted fashion, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man-in-the-middle_attack">man-in-the-middle attacks</a>—which, if we’re honest, is what this amounts to—become much more difficult.</p>

<p>Assuming you can’t run under HTTPS for one reason or another, how do you harden your <a href="https://adactio.com/journal/6246">web thang</a> against 3rd party manipulation you can’t control? What if Comcast’s JavaScript interferes with your own? Remember when <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/jan/28/sky-broadband-blocks-jquery-web-critical-plugin">Sky blocked jQuery for all of their customers</a>? That was a bad couple of hours for most UK-based internet users.</p>

<p>Comcast’s move only serves to remind us—yet again—that we don’t control how our sites are delivered or what our users see. Or rather we do, but only up to a point. So rather than focus on some ideal experience we expect everyone to have, we must focus on building great experiences that work in a variety of contexts and situations.</p>

<p>We need to develop <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demolition_derby#Vehicles">the 1964 Chrysler Imperial</a> of websites: Sites that soldier on even when they are getting pummeled from all sides. After all, browsers, plug-ins, users, networks, and, yes, even the very routers that deliver our connections all have a say in how (and what) content gets to our users.</p>

<p>I’ll leave you with this scary quote from the <cite>Ars</cite> piece:</p>

<blockquote cite="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2014/09/why-comcasts-javascript-ad-injections-threaten-security-net-neutrality/">
    <p>Security expert Dan Kaminsky said in an e-mail that JavaScript injection has the potential to break “all sorts of stuff, in that you no longer know as a website developer precisely what code is running in browsers out there. You didn't send it, but your customers received it.”</p>
</blockquote>


<p>Hooray!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The “Native” vs. “Stylable” Tug of War]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaron-gustafson.com/notebook/2014/native-vs-stylable-tug-of-war/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T08:21:47-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaron-gustafson.com/notebook/2014/native-vs-stylable-tug-of-war</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In his astute post <a href="//www.brucelawson.co.uk/2014/native-experience-vs-styling-select-boxes/">“‘Native experience’ vs styling select boxes”</a>, Bruce Lawson correctly identified a common tension in the web world:</p>

<blockquote><p>But why this urge to re-style page elements that end-users are familiar with? … Or is it that we love native look and feel, except when we don’t?</p></blockquote>

<p>Speaking as the guy who not only wrote JavaScript to help me create an accessible <code>select</code> element alternative, but who also made it <a href="http://d1b14unh5d6w7g.cloudfront.net/1590598563.01.S0ER.LXXXXXXX.jpg?Expires=1405686346&amp;Signature=DCT4Z0l75JQESDNyP0PVGVonuJYwY9XYtaTI3grX/RhdlLcXGRAVADJCB/N/fAj7GxLhEVzuXqstMebJIJ9Ip5I6kE7IKYt2F20F5EGD+1ghua9zKwyjS1e4KBgumMKzQytbcfIVX4dMr7XFzj26mScFKz9bSKtZT5jU1LU6hWM=&amp;Key-Pair-Id=APKAIUO27P366FGALUMQ">the focus of a case study (image)</a> in <a href="http://amzn.to/TaoffD">AdvancED DOM Scripting</a>, I am fully aware of the desire to have it both ways. I have not often seen the desire for both in a single individual, but it does happen in one particular instance occasionally.</p>

<p>Based on my own experience, I see the following arguments in favor of changing the display of a native control quite often:</p>

<ol>
<li>It doesn’t look good to me.</li>
<li>It is not “on brand”.</li>
<li>It clashes with our brand’s color scheme.</li>
<li>We want the web experience to feel like a native app.</li>
<li>It doesn’t behave how we think it should.</li>
</ol>


<p><em>(<abbr lang="it" title="nota bene: please note">n.b.</abbr> Browsers have done a pretty good job reducing the amount of color and the overall visual strength used in native controls to help them better blend in with a wide variety of designs, so clashes as mentioned in #3 happen far less often than they did nearly a decade ago.)</em></p>

<p>As the weathered, battle tested (and, admittedly, somewhat jaded) front-end dev that I am, I typically push back with one or more of the following:</p>

<h2>In Addressing Desired Design Changes</h2>

<p>In terms of aesthetics (addressing arguments 1, 2, and 3), I understand where you’re coming from. Native controls are not the most appealing things, but they are familiar to your users. A <code>select</code> box they see on your site that looks like the one they see on Wikipedia or their banking site will be immediately recognizable. Sure, the looks and feel may differ from browser to browser, but most people use only a small number of browsers throughout the day—at work, at home, on their device—and if you want to ensure the design of a form control feels “right” in the browser they are using, sometimes it’s best to let go of that control.</p>

<h2>In Addressing OS Parity</h2>

<p>I can understand the desire to have a form control in a web page look and feel like the same (or a similar) control within the native operating system (argument 4), but I am not sure that’s a rabbit hole you want to go down. Here’s why: Achieving exact design and functional parity between a native control and a web control quite often requires extra markup, a bunch of CSS, and a bit of JavaScript. Anything is achievable with unlimited time and budget, so it’s completely doable, but it would be good to estimate the cost to see if you still think it is a worthwhile endeavor.</p>

<p>Assuming it is, we then have the question of which operating system to model the control after. Or maybe you want to offer a different take on the control based on the operating system your user is using. In that case, we may need to multiply the original estimate by the number of operating systems you want to support. But it’s worth noting that, in the Android world, different device manufacturers often “skin” the operating system to look different from other ones. Sometimes they even do it on a device-by-device basis. We’ll need to figure out which ones you want to include in your native control matrix and multiply the estimate accordingly.</p>

<p>Then there’s maintenance. We’ll need to test these native-like controls on each of their corresponding platforms and test the script that determines which experience gets delivered to which device to make sure we’re not accidentally sending the wrong experience. We’ll also need to test the delivery script on every other browser in our test matrix to ensure it is not causing issues there.</p>

<p>What should we do when a new operating system version is rolled out? iOS, for example, has made radical shifts in the design of their native controls in each major release. We’ll probably want to create unique versions of the control for each version of each OS we support and we’ll need to keep tabs on upgrades so we don’t end up confusing our users if they visit our site in iOS 7 and have a control that looks like it’s from iOS 6. We’ll need to add the number of OS versions into the multiplier as well.</p>

<p>Ok, and finally: How many controls did you want to apply this approach to again?</p>

<p>Or we could use the native form control and it will just work.</p>

<h2>In Addressing Altered Behavior</h2>

<p>I completely agree that not all native controls work exactly how I would like, but there are several risks in changing the expected behavior of a native control.</p>

<p>First of all, there’s the possibility we could actually end up making the interface more confusing or that the change in behavior might not be exactly what our user’s wanted (either based on what they are used to or our mental model not aligning with theirs). In order to rule out these issues, we should run a few rounds of usability tests. These could be quick café tests or more formal studies depending on the budget.</p>

<p>Assuming our tests go well, we will need to maintain this code and do all of the requisite browser testing. And potentially upgrade our code as new browsers and browser versions come out. Depending on the complexity of the code, this could become a large requirement, but if it is ultimately in the service of making the web a better, more usable interaction environment, it could be worth it.</p>

<p>For what it’s worth, if we go this route and are successful, we should consider getting involved in the spec-writing process at the <a href="//w3.org">W3C</a> or  <a href="//whatwg.org">WhatWG</a>. We should contribute our recommended changes back to the community and share what we learned. If we make a compelling argument, perhaps our idea will become part of some future standard and we can taper off our browser testing when the change goes native.</p>

<hr>


<p>As you can probably tell, I’m not a really big fan of changing existing controls as I feel it can amount to a wasted effort. That said, if there are design improvements to be made—“design” in the true sense: being about how usable something is, not just how aesthetically-pleasing it is to someone (e.g. improving contrast, making the control more intuitive, etc.)—I’m willing to accept the change as something we <em>should</em> do and then work to make sure that change has been vetted and, if successful, given away for inclusion in other projects. If it solves a major issue on the web, I want to give that change every opportunity to make it into the appropriate spec by talking to the appropriate folks about it both in-person, in blog posts, and on the appropriate mailing list. If the change solves a problem in a specific browser, I want to see it incorporated into said browser and will file a bug report and try to build momentum around it by engaging the community.</p>

<p>Anyway, that’s my general position on augmenting native controls. What are your thoughts on the topic?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Grand Experiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://aaron-gustafson.com/notebook/2014/a-grand-experiment/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-07T20:46:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://aaron-gustafson.com/notebook/2014/a-grand-experiment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, a mere three years after my old “life blog” stopped working, I decided to scrap it and start fresh.</p>

<p>In my quest to learn something new (more on that in a forthcoming post), I decided to give <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> a whirl. We’ll see how it goes, but the content entry has gone well so far and the Octopress community has been pretty responsive to my requests. I just need to get used to the workflow.</p>

<p>In the spirit of openness, I’ve decided to host the new site on <a href="http://github.com">Github</a> as a <a href="https://pages.github.com/">Github Page</a>. This frees me up from worrying about hosting fees of course, but it also means this site can serve as an educational tool for those inclined to dig in to the work I do and want some introspection into the way I do it. You can <a href="https://github.com/aarongustafson/aarongustafson.github.io/">view (and fork) the whole darn thing</a> at your leisure.</p>

<p>Finally, I’m designing and building this site in the open and, for posterity, taking screen shot of the progress. The screenshots will go up in time as an animated GIF, but those of you who wish will be able to follow along at home or work, seeing how I typically piece together a site, layer by layer, using <a href="http://adaptivewebdesign.info">progressive enhancement</a>. So far it’s just the content, but that’s what I preach: content first.</p>

<p>Now it’s time to get back to it. Feel free to reach out if you have any questions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
